Guide to the Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials, 1792 - 2002, bulk 1836-1977 MS 493
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III: Research photocopies and notes, 1810-2002, 235696; (27 boxes)
  - Sub-series B: Photocopies, notes and correspondence relating to George Cruikshank materials and collections, arranged alphabetically by repository or location (state). The files contain correspondence and many contain photocopies and transcriptions of Cruikshank material. Dates for the transcrip
    - Royal Academy of Arts, 1989 January - February, 236070 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee, 1977 June, 236069 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Texas, Utah, undated, 236068 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - UMBC Maryland (transcriptions, photocopies), 1830-1876, 236067 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - University of Texas, 1980, 236066 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Victoria and Albert Museum, London (transcriptions), 1827-1877, 236065 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Vermont, Virginia, Washington, 1977 June - July, 236064 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Virginia, 1988, 236063 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Washington (transcriptions, photocopies), 1830, 236062 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Windsor Royal Archives, 1988 July, 236061 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - West Virginia, Wisconsin, Wyoming, 1977 June - 1978 March, 236060 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series C: Collections and Catalogs, 1824-2002, undated, 235945
    - This sub-series includes files relating to a number of collections and catalogs describing George Cruikshank material. A small number of exhibition catalogs are included. The Albert Cohn catalog is an extensive listing of the works of George Cruikshank, his illustrations for books, etchings and individual illustrations. A number of the collections (Bradburn, Clarke and others) contain transcriptions of letters and other manuscripts., 236058
    - Adler, Hannah collection catalog, 1996, 236057 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Borowitz, David, collection, exhibition catalog, "George Cruikshank and His Contemporaries," 1978, 236056 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Bradburn, Frank S., Red 1-74, 236055 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Bradburn, Frank S., Blue 1-58, 236054 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Bradburn, Cruikshank collection catalogs, undated, 236053 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Bradburn Cruikshank collection notes, 1974, undated, 236052 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Clark, (CA 6-84), 236051 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Catalog numbers below correspond to Albert Cohn's, George Cruikshank: A Catalogue Raisonné of the Work Executed During the Years 1806-1877 with Collations, Notes, Approximate Values, Facsimiles, and Illustrations. The files contain notes, correspondence, articles and other research material related to the illustrations., 236050
    - Cohn, 1-25, 236049 (Box 458, Folder 8)
    - Cohn, 14, 236048 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Cohn, 19, 236047 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Cohn, 22, 236046 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Cohn, 24, 236045 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Cohn, 69, 236044 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Cohn, 87, 236043 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Cohn, 96, 236042 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Cohn, 109, 236041 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Cohn, 114, 236040 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Cohn, 116, 236039 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Cohn, 179, 236038 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Cohn, 181, 236037 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Cohn, 184, 236036 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Cohn, 188, 236035 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Cohn, 194, 236034 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Cohn, 196, 236033 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Cohn, 197, 236032 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Cohn, 198, 236031 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Cohn, 199, 236030 (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Cohn, 232, 236029 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Cohn, 234, 236028 (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Cohn, 239, 236027 (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Cohn, 243, 236026 (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Cohn, 356, 236025 (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Cohn, 382, 236024 (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Cohn, 433, 236023 (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - Cohn, 435, 236022 (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Cohn, 471, 236021 (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Cohn, 569, 236020 (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - Cohn, 580, 236019 (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - Cohn, 615, 236018 (Box 45, Folder 39)
    - Cohn, 703, 236017 (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - Cohn, 777, 236016 (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - Cohn, 880-884, 236015 (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - Cohn, 900-904, 236014 (Box 45, Folder 43)
    - Cohn, 930-934, 236013 (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - Cohn, 1000-1004, 236012 (Box 45, Folder 45)
    - Cohn, 1030-1034, 236011 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Cohn, 1035-1039, 236010 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Cohn, 1205-1209, 236009 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Cohn, 1215-1219, 236008 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Cohn, 1270-1274, 236007 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Cohn, 1750-1754, 236006 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Cohn, 1755-1759, 236005 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Cohn, 1770-1774, 236004 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Cohn, 1795-1799, 236003 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Cohn, 1840-1844, 236002 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Cohn, 1875-1879, 236001 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Cohn, 1955-1959, 236000 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Cohn, 2040-2044, 235999 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Cohn, 2110-2114, 235998 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Cohn, 1745-1749, 235997 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Fellman, Robert D., Collection catalog, Illustrating Dickens, 2002, 235996 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - George Cruikshank: A Bicentennial Exhibition, 1992-1993, 235995 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Gough, John B., The Works of George Cruikshank, catalog (photocopy), 1890, 235994 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Gowen, James E., collection, exhibition catalog, 1977, 235993 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Harvard University - Widener, 1-127 (transcriptions), circa 1824-1831, 235992 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Harvard University - Widener, 128-279 (transcriptions), circa 1828-1838, 235991 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Harvard University - Widener, 280-403 (transcriptions), circa 1827-1830, 235990 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Jerrold (transcriptions), 1865, 1875, 235989 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - John Johnson collection of printed ephemera, Bodleian Library, Oxford University. Photocopies of the collection., 235988
    - Johnson, John, collection, box 2, 1832 April, 235987 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Johnson, John, collection, drafts and handbills, circa 1831-1878, 235986 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Johnson, John, collection, George Cruikshank correspondence, circa 1858-1874, 235985 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Johnson, John, collection, George Cruikshank correspondence, circa 1835-1872, 235984 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Johnson, John, collection, prescriptions (includes transcriptions), circa 1836-1888, 235983 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, John, collection, receipts and cheques, circa 1842-1875, 235982 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Johnson, John, collection, tickets and invitations, circa 1860-1875, 235981 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Johnson, John, collection, oversize materials, circa 1851-1879, 235980 (Box 49)
    - Kohler, C.C., cross references, 235979 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Massachusetts (Mott and Richards collections), circa 1851-1876, 235978 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Middlesex collection: Letters and papers of George Cruikshank, artist and caricaturist (1792-1878), as Lieutenant Colonel of the 48th Middlesex Rifle Volunteers, "The Havalocks.", 235977
    - Middlesex collection, accnum 534, collection guide and notes, 235976 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/1, 1854-1862, 235975 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/2, 1862-1863, 235974 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/3, 1862-1872, 235973 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/4, 1862-1869, 235972 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/5, 1863-1868, 235971 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/6, 1868, 235970 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/7, 1868-1869, 235969 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/8, 1862-1868, 235968 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/9(1), 1862-1869, 235967 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/9(2), 1862-1869, 235966 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/11, 1862-1869, 235965 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/12-13, 1861-1868, 235964 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Middlesex collection, 534/14, 1852-1889, 235963 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Princeton University, George Cruikshank collection, 1-100 (transcriptions), circa 1828-1872, undated, 235962 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Princeton University, George Cruikshank collection, 101-200 (transcriptions), circa 1834-1874, 235961 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Princeton University, George Cruikshank collection, 201-300 (transcriptions), circa 1834-1872, 235960 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Princeton University, George Cruikshank collection, 301-400 (transcriptions), circa 1849-1872, 235959 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Princeton University, George Cruikshank collection, 401-500 (transcriptions), circa 1873, undated, 235958 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University, George Cruikshank collection, 501-631, 633- 635 (transcriptions), circa 1846-1863, undated, 235957 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Princeton University, George Cruikshank, With Some Account of His Brother Robert Robert Cruikshank, by Percy Cruikshank, photocopy, circa 1880, 235956 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Princeton University, checklist, George Cruikshank holdings, 1977-1978, 235955 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Princeton University, Merle-Cruickshank correspondence, 1-94 (photocopies), circa 1820-1846, 235954 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University, Merle-Cruickshank correspondence, 95-189 (photocopies), circa 1846-1878, 235953 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Searle, Ronald, cross-references, 235952 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Searle, Ronald, catalog notes for Searle I-VIII, 235951 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - UCLA, Special Collections, 1-34 (transcriptions), circa 1862-1871, undated, 235950 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - UCLA, Special Collections, 35-69 (transcriptions), circa 1849-1875, undated, 235949 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - UCLA, Special Collections, 70-122 (transcriptions), circa 1824-1855, undated, 235948 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Vogler, Richard, collection, selections, 1978, 235947 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Other catalogs (regarding George Cruikshank letters), photocopies and transcriptions, 1848-1903, 235946 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series D: Photocopies, 1812 - 1988, 235767
    - Articles, offprints, notes and correspondence relating to works on or about George Cruikshank, his contemporaries, book arts and illustration, and British social history. Arranged alphabetically primarily by author, with a small number of files added by title or subject., 235944
    - Adburgham, Alison, Punch: A History of Manners and Modes, 1841-1940, 1961, 235943 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - [W. H.] Ainsworth and His Friends, undated, 235942 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Altick, Richard D., The Marvelous Child of the English Stage, 1945, 235941 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Ashbee, H.S., George Cruikshank, in Notes and Queries, notes, undated, 235940 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Barham, R.H.D., Life of R.H. Barham, 1845, 235939 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Bates, William, George Cruikshank: The Artist, the Humanist, and the Man, notes, 235938 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Bates, William, Maclise Portrait Gallery, 1883, 235937 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Bede, Cuthbert, A Reminiscence of George Cruikshank and His Magazine, 1878, 235936 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Beerbohm, Max, The Spirit of Caricature, in A Variety of Things, 1922, 235935 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Belchem, John, 'Orator' Hunt, Henry Hunt and English Working - Class Radicalism, 1985, 235934 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Benjamin, Walter, "Charles Baudelaire: A Lyric Poet in the Era of High Capitalism," "Illuminations," "The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction, 1988, 235933 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Bentley, Richard, "A Victorian Publisher (by Royal A. Gettmann), 1960, 235932 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Berry and Poole, Annals of Printing, 1966, 235931 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Biografĺa de un dibujante: George Cruikshank, 1985, 235930 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Blakey, Robert, Old Faces in New Masks, 1859, 235929 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Blanchard, Laman, 235928 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Bland, David, A History of Book Illustration, 1969, 235927 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Books Illustrated by Cruikshank, in The Bookseller, 1878, 235926 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Brantlinger, Patrick, The Spirit of Reform, 1977, 235925 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Brice and Fielding, Dickens Studies Annual, 1981, 235924 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Broadley, A.M., Napoleon in Caricature, 1911, 235923 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Browne, Hablot, notes, 235922 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Bryan and Stanley, Dictionary of Painters and Engravers, 1849, 235921 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Buss, Robert William, English Graphic Satire, 235920 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Butler, Marilyn, Romantics, Rebels, and Reactionaries, 1981, 235919 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Carr, J. Comyns, Essays on Art, 1879, 235918 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Carretta, Vincent, The Royal Dupe, in The Age of Johnson, 235917 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - A Catalogue of a Selection from the Works of George Cruikshank, 1799-1863, 235916 (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Chapman and Hall, undated, 235915 (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Chatto, William Andrew, A Treatise on Wood Engraving, 1891, 235914 (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Clarke, William, circa 1833, 235913 (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - Collier, J.P., An Old Man's Diary, 1872, 235912 (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - Collins, Philip, Dickens and Crime, 1962, 235911 (Box 56, Folder 24)
    - Comstock, H., How Robert Cruikshank Used the Bartlett View, 1934, 235910 (Box 56, Folder 25)
    - Cruikshank, George, A Pop-Gun, 1860, 235909 (Box 56, Folder 26)
    - Cruikshank, George, House Book, undated, 235908 (Box 56, Folder 27)
    - Cruikshank, George, Notes: Recollections of George Cruikshank, undated, 235907 (Box 56, Folder 28)
    - Cruikshank, Mary, "Commonplace Book" (notes), undated, 235906 (Box 56, Folder 29)
    - Dalziel, George and Edward, The Brothers Dalziel, undated, 235905 (Box 56, Folder 30)
    - Darton, F.J. Harvey, Children's Books in England, 1982, 235904 (Box 56, Folder 31)
    - Day, S. Phillips, notes, 235903 (Box 56, Folder 32)
    - De Mare, Eric, Victorian Woodblock Illustrations, 1981, 235902 (Box 56, Folder 33)
    - Dickens unpublished letters, notes, 235901 (Box 56, Folder 34)
    - Dohson, Austin, notes on the DNB listing for George Cruikshank, 235900 (Box 56, Folder 35)
    - Dodds, John W., The Age of Paradox, 1952, 235899 (Box 56, Folder 36)
    - Du Maurier, Daphne, The Young George Du Maurier, 1951, 235898 (Box 56, Folder 37)
    - Eichenberg, Fritz, The Art of the Print, 1976, 235897 (Box 56, Folder 38)
    - Ellis, S.M., William Harrison Ainsworth and His Friends, undated, 235896 (Box 56, Folder 39)
    - Emsley and Walvin, Artisans, Peasants, and Proletarians, 1985, 235895 (Box 56, Folder 40)
    - Epstein, James, Cap of Liberty, 1988, 235894 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Evans, Edmund, The Reminiscences of Edmund Evans, 1967, 235893 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Everitt, Graham, English Caricaturists of the 19th Century, undated, 235892 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Feaver, William, Cruikshank: The Artist's Role, 1974, 235891 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Feaver, William, Cruikshank for Posterity, 1978, 235890 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Findlater, Richard, Grimaldi, 1955, 235889 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Forques, Emile, La Caricature en Angleterre, 1854, 235888 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Frith, W.P., My Autobiography, 1888, 235887 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - George, M. Dorothy, English Political Caricature to 1792, 1959, 235886 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - George Cruikshank, in Blackwoods Edinburgh Magazine, 1863, 235885 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - The Georgian Era, 1832, 235884 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Gough, John B., Autobiography, 1869, 235883 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Gray, Bail, The English Print, 1937, 235882 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Graves, Algernon, The Royal Academy of Arts, 1905, 235881 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Haight, Sherman P., George Cruikshank, in Publisher's Weekly, 1928, 235880 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Hall, S.C., Retrospect of a Long Life, undated, 235879 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Hamerton, P.G., Etching and Etchers, 1912, 235878 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Hamilton, Walter, A Memoir of George Cruikshank, 1978, 235877 (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Hamst, Olphar, George Cruikshank, in Notes and Queries, 1878, 235876 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Hansard's Parliamentary Debates, 1862, 235875 (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Harvey, J.R., Victorian Novelists and Their Illustrators, notes, undated, 235874 (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Hawes, Donald, Marryat and Dickens, in Dickens Studies Annual, 1972, 235873 (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - Hertz, Neil, The End of the Line, 1985, 235872 (Box 57, Folder 23)
    - Hill, Draper, notes, 235871 (Box 57, Folder 24)
    - Hill, Nancy, notes, 235870 (Box 57, Folder 25)
    - Hind, Arthur, M., History of Engraving and Etching, 1963, 235869 (Box 57, Folder 26)
    - Hodder, George, Memories of My Time, undated, 235868 (Box 57, Folder 27)
    - Hofmann, Werner, Caricature, 1957, 235867 (Box 57, Folder 28)
    - Hood, Thomas, Complete Poetical Works, 1906, 235866 (Box 57, Folder 29)
    - Howard, Edward, Rattlin the Reefer, 1971, 235865 (Box 57, Folder 30)
    - Howell-Smith, Simon, International Copyright and the Publisher in the Reign of Queen Victoria, undated, 235864 (Box 57, Folder 31)
    - Humphries, Anne, Travels into the Poor Man's Country, 1977, 235863 (Box 57, Folder 32)
    - Jabet, Nasology, 1848, 235862 (Box 57, Folder 33)
    - James, Henry, Autobiography, undated, 235861 (Box 57, Folder 34)
    - Jerrold, Blanchard, Life of George Cruikshank, notes, 235860 (Box 57, Folder 35)
    - Jones, Mumford, The Comic Spirit and Victorian Sanity, in The Reinterpretation of Victorian Literature, 1950, 235859 (Box 57, Folder 36)
    - Kelly, Dawn P., Liberation or Restraint: The Demonic in the Works of George Cruikshank, in CEA Critic, 1985, 235858 (Box 57, Folder 37)
    - Knight, Charles, Passages of a Working Life, 1864, 235857 (Box 57, Folder 38)
    - Kris, Ernst, Psychology of Caricature, undated, 235856 (Box 57, Folder 39)
    - Krist and Gombrich, Principles of Caricature, undated, 235855 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Kroeber, Karl, Constable: Millais/Wordsworth: Tennyson, in Articulate Images, 1983, 235854 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Lamb, Charles, Drawing for Illustration, undated, 235853 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Lamb, Charles, On the Genius and Character of Hogarth, in Anecdotes of William Hogarth, 1833, 235852 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Layard, George S., notes, 235851 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Lectures on the Fine Arts, in Blackwood's Magazine, undated, 235850 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Ledue, undated, 235849 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Letters and Private Papers of W.M. Thackery, 1946, 235848 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - The Letters of Charles Dickens (nonesuch), notes and photocopies, 1938, 235847 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - The Letters of Charles Dickens, vol. 1-4 (Pilgrim), photosopies, 1835-1852, 235846 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Lindley, Kenneth, Woodblock Engravers, 1970, 235845 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Locker-Lampson, Frederick, My Confidences, 1896, 235844 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Loveridge, Mark, Laurence Sterne and the Argument about Design, 1982, 235843 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Mackay, Charles, Forty Years Recollections, 1877, 235842 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Mackenzie, Robert S., George Cruikshank, in The London Journal, 1847, 235841 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - McCalman, Iain, Radical Underworld, 1988, 235840 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - McLean, Ruari, George Cruikshank: His Life and Work as a Book Illustrator, undated, 235839 (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - McMaster, Juliet, Dickens the Designer, 1987, 235838 (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - Marten, Harry, Exaggerated Character: A Study of the Works of Dickens and Hogarth, in Dickens and Hogarth, 1976, 235837 (Box 58, Folder 19)
    - Marten, Harry P., The Visual Imagination of Dickens and Hogarth, in Studies in the Novel, 1974, 235836 (Box 58, Folder 20)
    - Maxwell, Christabel, Mrs. Gatty and Mrs. Ewing, [1949], 235835 (Box 58, Folder 21)
    - Merle, W.H., Melton de Mowbray: or the Banker's Son, 1838, 235834 (Box 58, Folder 22)
    - Moers, Ellen, The Dandy, 1960, 235833 (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - Morgan, E.S. Morgan, …a brief retrospective…, undated, 235832 (Box 58, Folder 24)
    - Muir, Percy, Victorian Illustrated Books, 1971, 235831 (Box 58, Folder 25)
    - Nadel and Schwartzbach, Victorian Artists and the City, 1979, 235830 (Box 58, Folder 26)
    - Oliver Twist, notes, 235829 (Box 58, Folder 27)
    - On George Cruikshank, in Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine, 1823, 235828 (Box 58, Folder 28)
    - Palgrave, Francis T., The Cruikshank Exhibition, in Essays on Art, 1867, 235827 (Box 58, Folder 29)
    - Parsons, Ian, Copyright and Society, in Essays in the History of Publishing, undated, 235826 (Box 58, Folder 30)
    - Parton, James, Caricature and Other Comic Art, 1877, 235825 (Box 58, Folder 31)
    - Past and Present: The Tower of London and Historical Illustration, essay, 235824 (Box 58, Folder 32)
    - Patten, Robert, George Cruikshank's Grimm Humor, 1988, 235823 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Patten, Robert, Who Wrote Oliver Twist, undated, 235822 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Paulson, Ronald, Emblem and Expression: Meaning in English Art of the Eighteenth Century, notes, 235821 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - A Peculiar Gift: Nineteenth Century Writings on Books for Children, 1976, 235820 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Pettigrew, Medical Portrait Gallery, notes, 235819 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Phillips, E. Watts, Watts Phillips: Artist and Playwright, 1891, 235818 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Porter, Roy, The Social History of Language, and an article on social medicine, 1988, 235817 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Reid, notes, 235816 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Reitlinger, Henry, From Hogarth to Keene, undated, 235815 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Richardson, B. Ward, notes, 235814 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Roger, J.C., Gallery of Comicalities, in Notes and Queries, 235813 (Box 59)
    - Rossetti, William M., Cruikshank, in Fine Art, Chiefly Contemporary, [1867], 235812 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Rossetti, William M., Fine Art, Chiefly Contemporary, 1867, 235811 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Rush, Richard, A Residence at the Court of London, 1833, 235810 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Ruskin, John, Works, notes, 235809 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Russell, Sturgis, George Cruikshank, in Scribners Monthly, 1878, 235808 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Sala, G. A., George Cruikshank: A Life Memory, in A Gentleman's Magazine, undated, 235807 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Sala, G. A., Life in Paris, in Atlantic Monthly, 1865, 235806 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Sala, G.A., Things I Have Seen and People I Have Known, 1894, 235805 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Salaman, Malcolm, British Book Illustration, 1923, 235804 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Schor, Naomi, Reading in Detail, 1987, 235803 (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Shikes, Ralph E., The Indignant Eye, 1969, 235802 (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Sitwell, S., Narrative Pictures, 1938, 235801 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Sitwell and Sacheverell, notes, 235800 (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - Slythe, Margaret, The Art of Illustration: 1750-1900, 1970, 235799 (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - Somerset House Gazette, 1824, 235798 (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Spencer, Walter, Forty Years in My Bookshop, undated, 235797 (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - Spielmann, M.H., History of Punch, 1895, 235796 (Box 59, Folder 28)
    - Stafford, B.M., Conjecturing the Unseen…,, 1985, 235795 (Box 59, Folder 29)
    - Steig, Michael, The Critic and the Illustrated Novel, in Huntington Library Quarterly, 1972, 235794 (Box 59, Folder 30)
    - Steiner, Wendy, Pictures of Romance, 1988, 235793 (Box 59, Folder 31)